Today, I sat down with Daniel Lev, the founder of CoinFlow. CoinFlow is a payment service provider
that uses stablecoins to offer faster settlement of both card payments and payouts for businesses.
Daniel's vision for CoinFlow was inspired by his previous work at e-commerce startups.
He had experienced delays and inefficiencies common in payment settlement and realized that
stablecoins could create a better offering. Without further ado, I hope you enjoy my conversation
with Daniel. Matt Walsh and Nick Carter are partners at Castle Island Ventures. All of these
expressed by them or the guests on this podcast are solely their opinions and do not reflect
the opinions of Castle Island Ventures. Guests and hosts may maintain positions in the assets
discussed in this podcast. You should not treat any opinion expressed by anyone on this podcast
as a specific inducement to make a particular investment or follow a particular strategy,
but only as an expression of their personal opinion. This podcast is for informational
purposes only. Brought down by bad mortgage investments, Lehman, which has 25,000 employees,
will be liquidated. The federal government loans American International Group, AIG, $85 billion.
This is a different kind of market and the Fed is asleep. The federal government is stepping in to
stabilize Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, the two mortgage giants that have been threatened by
the housing crisis. The Bank of England has pumped 75 billion pounds more into Britain's ailing
economy with a new round of quantitative easing. You print a couple trillion dollars and all of
a sudden people start to worry. So out of this worry, we have something called the Bitcoin.
Bitcoin. Daniel, thanks for coming on the podcast. Excited to chat today.
It's probably overdue at this point. I'd love for you to start by touching on what was the premise
for CoinFlow? Why did you guys start the business and what have you hoped to build from the day one?
That's a great question. Quick background is I've been building financial products for quite some
time in the quote unquote fintech space and I've been building crypto since I was an engineer in
college. And in between, I was at a hyper growth fintech. I was leading a big project in there.
We went through hyper growth, got pretty bloated. So I had some time to dabble in side projects.
Ended up starting a side project turned company. That was a fantasy sports protocol and so on.
We got a lot of free users and classic like VC back company that goes free,
strive freemium and convert. The free users couldn't convert because everything was on
blockchains and smart contracts. So you needed stable coins to buy things when people try to
convert. This was four and a half years ago. So people, you know, stable coins really were.
I barely knew what stable coins were when we're trying to use them in our project and no one who
convert. So we started using on ramps. Those had horrible conversion and I was pretty blown away
how like this infrastructure piece of like, hey, someone wants to pay you and you can't get paid
like doesn't exist for anyone in the crypto community. So it went down like a huge payments
rabbit hole and then realized that this doesn't exist. And what we were solving for is like,
hey, connect a traditional credit card or any form of payment acceptance to a smart contract.
And as soon as that form factor of like credit card is authorized, you can instantly the merchant
is being you didn't receive those funds. So that didn't exist. But if that existed, that would
actually like create order of magnitude improvement and what exists today in payment processing,
which is you swipe a card and takes three, four or five days for the merchant to get the money.
So I was like, okay, someone should build this. We'll build it in-house built it in-house. And
then people started asking us like, hey, who's like your infrastructure under the hood?
And immediately we're like, okay, I've seen this writing on the wall like I've seen this before
because the other startup I was at became a new corn. It started as a neo bank that created their
own loan iteration software and banks started asking for it. I was like, okay, this is great.
Like I've seen this before people are asking for this product. We don't have it.
Let's totally spin this out. And my background is building this. So yeah, we built it TLDR built
out of self need, but like going down the rabbit hole, like that self need, we understood the market
and like the general gap for it and decided to dive into it. And since then, it's just like
more and more revelations of like how deeply the system is broken and leaving us like for tons of
room of innovation. You touched on this, but what actually happens with a card payment today?
Let's start there.
Yeah. I mean, at a super high level, there's like a few different players.
There's a card network. So your Visa, MasterCard, Amex, Discover, et cetera, your merchant. So the
person that, hey, you were a consumer buying something from there is the issuer. So the person
that issues the card to the consumer that swipes your card. And then on the other side of that,
for the merchant, there's a payment service provider, someone like CoinFlow and oftentimes
an acquiring bank. So someone that helps underwrite and communicate to the card networks.
All those parties have to communicate. And what's gotten really good in terms of user
experience is people swiping the cards. Like the consumer has no issues with that, right?
You swipe your card, you see right away that the payment's authorized. So the payment service
provider helps the merchant capture that payment. So within seconds, you know, like, hey, why it has,
or whoever the user is, has money in their accounts and it's going to be good.
And it will eventually get to the merchants after that step. So like after it says, hey, money is
there, you're good to go. That's where the money starts moving between all those counterparties.
And things happen very, very, very slowly. So that's where really like the core of it
is. And a lot of the, I would say, industry and innovation has happened on the front end,
making sure that it's like super easy for you, the end user to spend your money.
And even in post-fact, spending your money, like you're insured, like if something goes wrong,
you can call to the bank and say, hey, like I was buying an ice cream cone from Dan.
He promised me vanilla, gave me chocolate. Like I should get a refund.
So that whole process is like very smooth and I would say more or less solved. But for the
businesses, like when I sold you that ice cream cone in this hypothetical instance, it took me
three days to get my money because what happens as soon as it's authorized, then the issuer
gets pulled their funds, which is the person in the bank that issued your card. They get their
money pulled. The card network is the middleman. They give it to the acquiring bank and the
acquiring bank has to send it to the payment service provider, payment service provider,
so it will release those funds to the merchant. And all those are on traditional banking rails.
And if you're doing that transaction globally, then it's like via the SWIFT network, which
adds counterparty banks. And if there's one bank holiday in one country or one delay somewhere,
then like that whole food chain can slow down. So until we are.
Yeah, it's like a system that's been built for comfort for the end user with a host of structural
debt underneath. That's a very good summary. Exactly. It's been built for the consumer,
the ton of structural debt, but it works for them. So like the average person is not complaining.
Right. And it's funny because one of the pushbacks I get on stable coins, particularly in the US,
is people will say, oh, my card network or my card payments works very well. Like I don't have any
issues. And it's this point that it's built to suit that person, but maybe not the vendor or maybe
not someone else who's involved in that chain. Yeah, totally. Like I use stable coins in business,
obviously, every day. And our company uses it 100,000 times a day in transactions. But as an end
user, I use my card in order of magnitude more. I think that's like because of the rewards,
everything else we get with it. So I totally get that. I don't know if stable coins will fully
replace... I don't want to go down this rabbit hole, but as of right now, there's no stable coin
product that means the end user would rather use my credit card for day-to-day purchases.
But if I'm buying something that cards can't accept, so like a high ticket item, I'm paying
my rent, I'd much rather do that via a stable coin. I think rent payments are like a mortgage
or a card payment, something like that that's larger that someone won't accept a credit card
for. That makes sense with stable coins. So I totally get where your friends or people are
coming from. So how does CoinFlow's workflow compare to the traditional payments networks
that you mentioned? Yeah, so in that process, let's just go back to that ice cream shop example.
I own an ice cream shop. I sell you ice cream cone. In that traditional example, let's say we're using
like a legacy provider, let's call it like Stripe. As soon as you swipe your card and it says,
hey, authorized ice cream cone, and I give you the ice cream cone, then it takes Stripe has to
release those funds. Once they get it, let's say they get it instantly from their bank,
which is impossible. Let's say they do. They still have to release those funds to me, the ice cream
owner and some type of bank payments. Let's call that ACH because that's most banks, not all banks
take real-time payments. It's going to be ACH. That takes one to three business days. It's Tuesday,
quick guess, I'll get my money on Wednesday evening, but likely Friday. That's like if I'm
the ice cream shop owner using Stripe. I'll get my money one to three days from when you paid.
CoinFlow, what we do as soon as you swipe your card, we get that authorization
because we know the money is coming from the card networks. We trust Visa will give us the money
they're legally obligated to. As soon as the card swipe happens, we instantly settle funds
to the ice cream shop's owner in their digital wallet via stable coins. It looks like a bank
dashboard where they have money in their wallet. It says US dollars. Then if they hit withdraw,
if they want to move it to their bank account, we can then instantly pay out to that bank account
or do it through that same bank payout method. It's there instantly. It can be used. We can
attach a credit card into the spend. It can be sent cross-border. It can be done with whatever,
if they send it to another vendor, whatever it is. That's the difference. Instead of waiting
one to three business days, they get their money in five seconds.
Are you guys funding that leg off of your balance sheet or do you have access to a line of credit
or how do you ensure that you can maintain that instant settlement when you might have times where
there's a lot of flow coming in? Yeah, a little bit of all the above. Some of it is balance sheet
capital. Some of it is partner capital. Then a lot of it is payouts as well. We get tons of payouts
of people like, hey, I actually don't need my money for three days. So I'm going to choose a
cheaper payout option. I think yesterday we had like a $10 million, I think ACH of wire and they're
like, yeah, we need to get the funds on Friday. So that goes into our liquidity engine and that
ice cream shop owner can leverage that. That goes into play as well. A little bit of all above.
And then the cool thing is that we are starting to get settlements from acquiring banks, none of the
U.S. have been in Europe via stablecoins five days a week and Visa is rolling that out seven days
a week. So yeah, not only is it structurally an issue that payment service providers can't
give their merchants funds 24-7-365, but the card networks don't actually have ways to access,
send their payment service providers a coin flow. Let's say this was, let's go back to the
Stripe example. If Visa wanted to settle faster, they actually couldn't. We're aware right now
without stablecoins. So Visa and other card networks are rolling out pilots and yeah,
we're starting to settle, get those funds seven days a week. It's not going to be T plus five
seconds like coin flow does it, but that window on like fronting it goes down. So there's definitely
some man behind the curtain going on that we're solving for with both like financial products,
balance sheet, our own liquidity engine. But it's cool to see that gap diminish. And we have all the
infrastructure and technology to manage those different ledgers because you're managing an
instant ledger, which is the blockchain with traditional rails. So you're connecting those
two together, not only moving money between them, but like connecting those two ledgers and marrying
them together, which you've all done in-house in the like battle test out scale. And maybe
stating the obvious, your guy's job would become much easier if initial payments actually started
to become made in stablecoins because then you just become an orchestrator of stablecoins to
whoever the end recipient is or the middleman that you need to route to, correct?
Yeah, that's right. Like we take in the stablecoin payments today. I don't know if much easier. It's
just a little bit different. Like we orchestrate between a bunch of different payment methods.
And in no world is there going to be like one payment acceptance winner of some type of method,
right? Like today, even for example, we have merchants who do 95% of their volume in credit
cards, but they still have like 3% acceptance in bank payments and then like 2% acceptance
in stablecoins or evidence. And even though like in my mind, bank payments is a way should your
options pay for like, I don't know, this is a red bull, like to buy a red bull, right? But if 3% of
your users want to do it, you're not going to be like, oh no, screw 3% of my revenue. I'm not going
to accept it. So the job of people at CoinFlow is going to be accept a larger amount of payment
options and continue to drive the speed of settlement down to closest instant. So I think
that's why like stablecoins, I'm so bullish as an infrastructure play, because it's really the only
way to connect all these very disparate systems and get as close to real time as possible for
settlement. I'm a believer that over time we'll have more rather than less payment methods too.
When a lot of these software companies become fintechs at the same time and you have money
accounts associated with a lot of them and you'll probably have a rise of more digital banks,
curious for your perspective, but that's the way I see things going.
A hundred percent. There's more and more payment networks. So like, yeah, I guess like that digital
bank example you called out or apps that become like more fintech that you can pay with those
balances. See, I think there's going to be more and more payment networks, both crypto networks,
traditional fintech network, et cetera. But there needs to be a way to like interoperate them,
because the goal of if you have money in an account, those people want to monetize in those
balances. And the only way to monetize on them is one, keep them in there or to like allow them to
spend those balances. So if they spend those balances, they need a way to transact. And like
the only way to do that easily globally is either through like issuing a card off that balance
or to making a stablecoin of your transfer. So you touched on payouts and we've talked about
payments acceptance. Could you highlight CoinFlow's range of offerings and at the same time
where you guys have gone based on where you see gaps in offerings from Stripe,
Adyen, Shift4 and larger existing payments players?
Yeah, for sure. I would say there's like two main products. One is like allowing
our merchants to accept payments globally and instantly receive funds instead of waiting
buckle days. So like all those people you said, at least one, two business days to get your money,
we do in five seconds. And then also none of them help you like get rid of fraud. They help you
prevent some of the fraud. The difference between CoinFlow is like we'll eat all the chargeback
risk. So the value prop is like, hey, get your money instantly and don't lose any money to fraud.
So that's what the payment acceptance side. But once you get your money, a lot of businesses,
marketplaces, remittance companies, gaming companies, crypto exchanges,
anything that has a consumers that need to cash out, fintechs, etc. will not only receive money
from users but need to pay out to their end users. So there's a payout component and that's other
products. We have that in like 70 plus countries. I would say the biggest gap that we've seen in the
market is combining those two products together. So when all those types of companies like especially
marketplaces where you have, let's say that ice cream shop example, let's say there is,
I don't know, digital marketplace for ice cream shops and you can buy these gift cards.
Now I'm the marketplace and I have all these sellers on my site. You're buying stuff from them.
So not only do I have end users consuming and spending, you also need to go pay out these ice
cream shop owners and they can be globally. So I think connecting those two products between
ledgering, holding funds on platform, which is very easy to like digital wallets, fraud, etc.
That's probably the biggest gap we've seen in the market. And then there's just a lot of payout gaps
because of how pre-funding works. So connecting stablecoins to that has been like a huge,
huge win. I'll give you an example. So like say you are a business in the US and you need to pay out
suppliers over the weekend or whatever it may be. You can pay people out through Visa Direct. If
there's small purchases up to 50 grand Visa Direct. So you enter your debit card and get paid out
or real-time payment network. But to get there, you actually pre-fund the bank account to be a
buyer. So like before 5 p.m. on Friday. So if you don't get your wire in like 2 p.m. on Friday,
you actually can't use a real-time payment network. So it's kind of contradicting.
Let's say you don't get your wire in, but you send stablecoins to us. That's still a proof of good
funds. We know that money's there and then we can burn those funds and then pay off from that
balance over the weekend. So this like pre-funding dilemma has more or less been solved if you can
use stablecoins for payouts. So that's another big gap. I think the biggest gap is still that like
connecting the pay in and payout piece and making both instance. People have done a good job of
making like the payout piece instant by pre-funding, but it's not like all that instant if you have to
use your own balance sheet or somehow figure out a way to pre-fund before bank hour close.
Yeah, definitely. That example is helpful. It makes a lot of sense.
You touched on the fraud piece. I think that's easy to overlook. How do you guys eat the risk
of fraud? That seems very attractive if I were a vendor, for example.
Yeah, no, it definitely is. So the play really is like it's an AI model and it's mixed between like
insurance and a fraud model. It's going more and more towards like the fraud model and insurance is
like making sure that we can cover it fully. The fraud model has like 100,000 variables
and it's an AI model. So it continuously learns as fraud attacks happen. Fraud is like a cat and mouse
game where like you find the problem, you stomp it and then like they come back like whatever
interval, hopefully in months or years later, but they keep finding new routes. And that's why like
the AI is so helpful because if you have a deterministic model, so for example, like what
that means is, hey, Wyatt is a fraudster and he is figuring out that I'm the ice cream shop owner
and if I buy a $500 ice cream cone or more, we actually don't do any checks because we think
that's like a VIP customer. They want gold sprinkled in the ice cream cone and that's like super low
risk to us. So say you as Wyatt the fraudster figure that out and only buy gold sprinkled ice cream
cones now. Me as an ice cream shop owner in like two or three weeks, I get those chargebacks.
I'll figure out like, oh, hey, like maybe we actually shouldn't allow people to buy $500
ice cream cones or do like really strong KYC, make Wyatt tell us his kid's first name,
do an eyeball scan, which is going to kill conversion. So that's why these deterministic
models don't really work because like, sure, you can stop it. You can find out what's happening,
duct tape it. But when you duct tape it, you actually kill real users. But these AI models
will learn really quickly. Okay, like we used to only sell one gold plated ice cream cone a month.
We sold 10 today. Like what is going on? And the model will learn, hey, saying this is suspicious
activity. Let's stop it. The other beauty is unlike the blockchain and what the car networks
are starting to embrace and at least these have put in the rules is something like proof of
deliverability. So in the ice cream example, it doesn't really work well because it's a physical
good. Well, let's just say like a digital good, a Fortnite skin is a good example. If you were
dispute right now in Fortnite, like, hey, I didn't get my skin. There's really no good way for the
car network to have insight into if that good was delivered to you because it's a digital good.
How that good is delivered is a switch in for nice database, like saying, hey, why it's a count?
Why is the beast now has the dragon skin? Very, very hard to prove because like Fortnite,
it's not going to be like, hey, here we say, here's my database keys. Go see this. I'll just
show like an email. It can be altered. It's not very good. It doesn't win with blockchain.
Everyone can see it, including the PSP that the item was delivered right away if it's shown on
chain. So you can actually see the transaction happen like, hey, why I paid with the card funds
were sold to the merchant and that same transaction that skin was released.
That transaction can be attached to the payment to visa while a transaction happens.
So if a dispute then later happens, we can be like, hey, no, why saying he never got this?
Look, look, visa, look, bank that was actually given. So that's still like very early days.
But for a lot of use cases, there's like the digital goods. It works very well. It even works
better for things like remittance or when people are popping up into accounts,
for example, like adding money to an exchange. Very hard to argue if you have a wallet
that has received sample coins that you didn't actually get those sample coins.
It's very easy to prove in a matter of seconds and you can tie it to that exact transaction.
So there's a ton of innovation happening there behind the scenes, which isn't like talked about
because one, it's early and it's not sexy. But I read something the other day that like a
hundred billion dollars of losses happened to merchants last year just by friendly fraud.
What that means is like people know that if they call our bank and complain
that something wasn't right with the thing they bought, the bank will likely sound at them,
which is called friendly fraud. Even though that, hey, like this red bull tasted funny,
the bank will probably honor that. And now the merchant has a chargeback.
And I, as a consumer, just got my like $5 back for this red bull. So yeah, there's a lot of
innovation happening there and I'm excited to see. I think it will like definitely be a sleeper to
look for in the next few years. Yeah. I mean, from my perspective, there are
just multiple layers of compensation and issues happening. Like the banks are willing to eat that
because they get to keep essentially all of the interest or whatever they're making on your
deposits and that business is too good. So they'll pay you back for your red bull. But
realistically, then in a way it becomes the end merchant losing, which is a messed up system. So
there's a lot to be fixed. A single ledger to your point is very attractive, I think,
when it comes to tracking something like fraud. Have you guys built your fraud engine in-house
or what are you using? Yeah, I would say our fraud engine is in-house
and then like any other fintech, we've bundled like 10 different providers.
See, we have a bunch of different providers, whether we're using even like some AI models,
we have Gemini, we have another platform that has their own AI model called insure.ai.
We use them for part of the insurance. We have our own engine that plugs into all these things
and calculates the risk of fraud. Plus a lot of it is like data orchestration to feed into these
models. So yeah, I think most things in fintech are built as close to the rails as possible.
And like orchestrated together without end users knowing anything's there. It just works.
In the backdrop of some innovation, similar to what we've been talking about, where you're having
more pay with crypto cards, pay with stocks, pay with treasuries type payment cards. Do you think
the fraud tooling and infrastructure anti-fraud mechanisms are getting better? Are you seeing
interesting innovation on that front, especially when it comes to more on-chain assets,
more assets of different types, et cetera? I would say they're getting better. Nothing has
been fully cracked yet. And I think it's because it's so early and only in the last year or two
have been like a new wave of companies building and innovating just generally around the stable
coin space. There's market leaders like Coinbase, Circle, Altair, there's been people doing it.
But now we have hundreds of companies. And when you're a market leader like Coinbase, Tether,
whatever, Circle, you all have your own fraud teams. Sure, you need this infrastructure,
but at some point you're like, this doesn't exist. We're just going to have our own team
building internally. But when there's hundreds of thousands of companies, technology, every company
can't just have their own fraud team, figure it out. You want to use infrastructure providers
or at least supplement it. So I think that's where the innovation stemming of like, okay,
now there is a bunch of demand for people to build this type of apps or infrastructure,
and then there'll be other infrastructure to support it. So that's what we're seeing here.
I think it's still pretty early days though. Do that make sense? And it seems like over time,
regardless, these more complex types of transactions like global are going to be more
advantaged. I was curious to ask you in that vein, how much of what you guys do is US to non-US or
non-US to US versus domestic? Yeah, I think we're probably in a very unique spot in terms of most
stable coin companies, quote unquote, right? Most of our volume is US, probably at least 75% is like
both pans and pads are domestic. And it just shows because like, our banking rails are so archaic
and so slow that, yeah, speeding up payments using a better rail in between is the example.
I think like the best example is our biggest category now is marketplaces. So when there's
a merchant is the marketplace and there's buyers and sellers on both sides.
This is for digital goods or real goods or could be either?
It can be anything. It can be anything. I think the issue with these companies right now is
the money movement is very slow. And you tell any marketplace, like I got my haircut this week
and I use the marketplace called Squire. It's a place for barbers. So my barber,
instead of like setting up a Stripe account, managing taxes, managing like the booking,
Squire does that. Squire is a marketplace and all the barbers have to do is go sign in.
He enters the dates and you can pay there. You can do everything there.
On Squire, they use Stripe. My barber gives me a haircut on Friday. I pay via Stripe. He
gives his money Tuesday. I asked that same barber like, hey, would you want to get paid today?
His answer is going to be like, yes, I want to get paid today. My girlfriend,
my friends want to get drinks. I would love to use the money I made today from your tip
to go buy everyone drinks. Can't happen, right? Coincidentally, Stripe most of their volume,
I think 70% of their volume or something, 60 to 75. I don't know exact numbers. Majority
comes from their marketplace product. So you can think about this as like everyone who's selling
an item through that marketplace is like, hey, I want to get my money faster and they can't.
And that's all domestic. Like my barber is domestic, et cetera. And that's Stripe's volumes,
mainly domestic too. So the long story is most of volumes US, unlike most stable coin companies,
but there's still huge things that are broken in very large industries like marketplaces
in the US that just having a stable coin in the back end can make way more efficient.
In that example, do you think the cost of delivering a free payment will come down
to zero or an instant payment, I should say? Or do you think that there will be some kind
of a credit market there where you're paying some rate in order to get instant payments versus
whatever would be a two, three day latency? I don't think it'll go to zero because it
doesn't need to go to zero. Consumers are willing to pay a lot, like right now, a lot of money for
it, right? I don't know what the average rate to borrow is right now, but it's 8% for a year-ish,
right? Even if you're a small business, yeah. Let's call it 8 to 10, right? Let's call it 10
high side. Consumers are paying like 200 basis points, 2% to get one payment instantly from Venmo,
Coinbase, Cash App, et cetera. And most people on Venmo are doing the instant payments,
that's in the US. So every time they receive a payment, that's 2%. So that one payment that
they just paid for instant payment is 25% of the cost of capital to take that as a business for a
year. So you can think about how many times that could get recycled. And sure, it might be cheaper,
but it won't go to zero because people are just willing to pay for it. And if it's marginally
more expensive, let's call it, instead of 2%, the majority of people on Venmo are willing to pay 2%,
let's cut it 90% and call it like 20 basis points. That's still a solid margin. And on the credit
market, that's still pretty good for one transaction. So I think there's like a lot of room to play with
even if it goes down 90%. Yeah, I completely agree. In the three years you've been working on
in this area, essentially, how has the environment around you changed, both from a perspective of
companies and regulatory attitudes? Yeah, I mean, companies, there wasn't many people
building this. It was all very crypto centric. I would say infrastructure was only being I mean,
people talked about like, letting non crypto customers use crypto rails. Since I've been in
crypto for the last like decade, like, oh, yeah, people are gonna use Bitcoin, people use this and
that same thing in stable coins. Like there was some, I think the 2020 bull market saw some of
that people come on chain, or businesses come on chain, primarily NFTs. And I think a lot of like
PR stunts, even ones that did wall got shut down, like DraftKings had an NFC marketplace that did
pretty well and they shut it down. Or it did really well relative to other NFC marketplace,
and they still shut it down. It probably didn't do as well as their actual business that makes
money. So there just wasn't many businesses servicing anything outside of crypto and crypto
was just really down. But I think there was like a cohort of believers of like, hey, like,
this core structure does work. And it's just a matter of time. And then between like the 2021
2022 bear market happened, or like bull market ended to a bear market. It was pretty crazy,
because most people that were building infrastructure were servicing crypto companies,
a number of crypto companies went down. So like, your core ICP shrunk. And then not only that
happened, but regulatory environment got more hostile. So if you're building in something
that's like financial, they were cracking down on banks in the US, plus on crypto.
So like, your ICP is going down, and people are out to get you. So that was a pretty crazy time
the last few years. And then I would say like right around the Trump election, some companies
are getting scale, using stable coins as infrastructure, the larger companies weren't
slowing down. And more and more companies like coin flow and others started getting
traditional web two businesses to use and adapt these tools. And then I think there's a bunch
of catalysts, but probably the Trump election just sparked a huge insurgence of like, businesses
want to learn more about stable coins, using stable coins. And then you basically saw like
every major fintech, and even some before the Trump admin, like PayPal is one that you can call
out because like, they launched PayPal usb and started talking about stable coins, during the
Biden administration, etc. But then there's, and Visa was doing this, there's only a few call out
and I was telling banks like, hey, look, PayPal is doing it, Visa is doing it, trust me, it's
going to be a thing. And then, so people started like looking at it. But they still looked at it
like a little weird or squinted. And then when Trump got elected, and acquisitions are happening,
every fintech star announced their self stable coins came from like sideline to like, oh my gosh,
everyone has to go and at least do research and development and make a press release if they're
doing research development about it. So yeah, huge tailwinds on like fintechs. And then from merchants,
or like from businesses that we serve, I would say the biggest change has been like,
they're seeing that news, they're seeing that like, hey, like this isn't going away. And
consensus, this is a better tool. I think they were just scared, like,
talking in person about it, like, cool, they get all the value process. But then again,
the tools are using, they work, there's a way to optimize it. But the mental model they were
looking at was like, okay, we can get our money instant. But the thing we're getting the money
through stable coins, you know, it's all infrastructure. But let's say the Biden
administration got elected again, or whoever got elected, and they were like anti like,
they could just make that illegal. Now, like, sure, we're getting this thing faster. But the
company that servicing us came and operated more. So that's not a huge one. So that risk is out of
the picture now, which is awesome. Yeah, it's an important point. It feels like there's a
sustainability now. Dan, in closing, I wanted to ask to that point you just made, if there is a
seller of goods, a vendor out there who is in this paradigm, where you take a payment on Friday,
you receive funds on Tuesday, how should they proceed towards trying to iterate towards
next generation instant ask payment system internally?
Yeah, I mean, they can just talk to us and we can do it all for them. So yeah,
if they want to get in contact with us, we're very reachable, like our websites coin flow dot cash.
Or you can hit me up on my Twitter or I'm sure it'll be attached to this. But yeah,
reach out to anyone from the coin flow team and we're happy to help and map out your flow funds,
map out your roadmap, etc. Yeah, I think this is where the world's going. Because the value
prop is very simple. It's hard to find someone who doesn't want to get paid
for what they're doing as soon as they do it. Yeah, makes sense. Well, Dan, thanks for joining
us and hopefully we can sit down again sometime soon. Yeah, man. Thanks for having me. It's been
a pleasure. Thanks for listening to another episode of On the Brink with Castle Island.
To find out more about Castle Island, visit castleisland.vc. To listen to all of our podcast
episodes, please go to onthebrink-podcast.com or just click on the tab in our website. Thanks for
listening.